<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on TinyGo - Go on Microcontrollers and WASM</title>
    <link>https://tinygo.org/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on TinyGo - Go on Microcontrollers and WASM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 11:41:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tinygo.org/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux</title>
      <link>https://tinygo.org/getting-started/linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 11:41:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinygo.org/getting-started/linux/</guid>
      <description>This page has information on how to install and use TinyGo on Ubuntu, as well as other Linux distros.
If you want to use TinyGo to compile your own or sample code, you can install the release version directly on your machine by following the &amp;ldquo;Quick Install&amp;rdquo; instructions below.
You can instead install the full source code to the TinyGo compiler itself, generally for people who wish to contribute to the project or want to build the compiler from sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS</title>
      <link>https://tinygo.org/getting-started/macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 11:41:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinygo.org/getting-started/macos/</guid>
      <description>This page has information on how to install and use TinyGo on macOS.
If you want to use TinyGo to compile your own or sample code, you can install the release version directly on your machine by following the &amp;ldquo;Quick Install&amp;rdquo; instructions below.
You can also install the full source code to the TinyGo compiler itself, generally for people who wish to contribute to the project or want to build the compiler from sources directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows</title>
      <link>https://tinygo.org/getting-started/windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 11:41:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinygo.org/getting-started/windows/</guid>
      <description>This page has information on how to install and use TinyGo on Windows 10.
Quick Install If you want to use TinyGo to compile your own or sample code, you should be able to install the release version directly on your machine using Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) by following the &amp;ldquo;Quick Install&amp;rdquo; instructions on the Linux page located here.
Docker Install The other option is to use the Docker image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker</title>
      <link>https://tinygo.org/getting-started/using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinygo.org/getting-started/using-docker/</guid>
      <description>You can use our Docker image to be able to run the TinyGo compiler on your computer without having to install all the dependencies. Read on to learn how.
Installing docker pull tinygo/tinygo  Using A docker container exists for easy access to the TinyGo CLI. For example, to compile wasm.wasm for the WebAssembly example, from the root of the repository:
docker run --rm -v $(pwd):/src tinygo/tinygo tinygo build -o /src/wasm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>